# **Ann-Cathrin Will - Front-end Developer**

Woking, Surrey ann@cathrinwill.com

#### **Profile**

I'm an experienced Front-end Developer having worked at a variety of digital and marketing agencies for over 3 years. With strong skills in writing HMTL and CSS, utilising Sass and grunt for development

I enjoy a challenge and look for the opportunity to expand and develop my skill sets. My portfolio website is: <a href="https://www.cathrinwill.com">www.cathrinwill.com</a>

## Skills Summary

#### **Core Skills**

- HTML(Excellent)
- CSS(Excellent)
- Sass/SCSS (Good)
- LESS (Satisfactory)
- iQuery (Good)
- JavaScript (Satisfactory)
- Grunt (Satisfactory)

- Responsive Design
- Progressive enhancement
- W3C Standards & Accessibility
- Usability & UX considerations
- · Cross browser compatibility
- Github
- Adobe Suite

## Professional Experience

## Front end Developer at Purple Agency

March 2013 - Present

- Building front-end responsive templates based on supplied designs using SCSS/LESS and grunt/gulp.
- · Cross browser and A/B testing.
- · Building and setting up email campaigns.
- · Keeping clean and maintainable code.
- · Staying up to date with web trends and new technologies.
- · Ensuring websites are accessibility friendly.
- Using semantic code, meta/micro data, and Google analytics, to ensure SEO for sites.
- Using a combination of git, bitbucket, SourceTree and SVN for version control.

### Front end Developer at Webexpectations

September 2012 – March 2013

- Building the front end from Photoshop/Illustrator templates, and creating standalone pages for multivariate testing.
- Experience gained from working with a variety of CMS'.
- Working with development processes including Git for version control.
- Experience with responsive web development and mobile / retina display optimisation.
- Built HTML Emails and HTML email signatures.

# **Ann-Cathrin Will - Front-end Developer**

Woking, Surrey ann@cathrinwill.com

## Night Receptionist at Premier Inn

September 2009 – September 2012

Weekend job throughout attending University.

Junior Web Developer at SuperReal GmbH, Germany April 2007 – October 2007

Work experience in Hamburg learning how to make websites, working with Graphic Designers and using Photoshop and Integrating Front-end code with code written by Backend developers. Taking extra care to make websites identical across browsers including such challenges as IE6/7 and the box model bug.

#### Education

### Web Development with Business BSc (Hons), Kingston University 2009 – 2012

- Learned the foundations to several previously self taught languages.
- Got a basic understanding of a variety of web languages.
- Worked in a lot of groups often taking on the role of organiser within it.
- Always ensured to hand in every coursework before the deadline.
- Helped peers with their work, and vice versa learned a lot from them.
- Thoroughly enjoyed working on the Single Semester Final Year Project, the end result which can be viewed on http://pixxy.cathrinwill.com/

# **Computer Information Systems and Mathematics Foundation** 2008 – 2009 Kingston College, Kingston upon Thames

# GCE 'A' Levels, Strode's College, Egham 2004 – 2005 German (A2), Biology (AS), Psychology (AS) and General Studies (GCSE)

# **GCSEs, Langley Grammar**, Slough 11 GCSEs – including Maths, Science and English Grade C and above

#### Interests

My interests include walking around hills, beaches, and forests with my friends. Reading books aimed at teenage girls and then not telling anyone I read books so they don't ask what I read. And listening to Netflix while looking at my phone/Imgur.

#### Languages

English (Bilingual proficiency)
German (Bilingual proficiency)

#### References

Available on request.